SAHEEDAT AFOLABI

CAREER SUMMARY

Front End Engineer with over 2 years of experience working on multiple projects across different frameworks and libraries while improving knowledge of frontend technologies.

Address: Lagos

LinkedIn: Saheedat Afolabi

Portfolio: <u>Saheedatt</u>
Phone: +234 904 508 5702
Email:afolabisaheedat1@gm

ail.com

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript/TypeScript.

FRAMEWORKS: Vue.js, Nuxt, React.js, Next.js, Tailwind CSS.

TECHNICAL SKILLS: API Integration, Testing, Accessibility.

SOFT SKILLS: Teamwork, Time Management, Problem Solving, Effective

communication

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FUSIONE, Althub.

FEBRUARY 2024 - JUNE 2024

— TEAM LEAD & FRONT END ENGINEER

- Led a diverse team of 16 members from various technical and business backgrounds i.e data team, product team and engineering team to develop Fusione, a platform that is designed to unify banking systems.
- Facilitated effective communication and collaboration among team members.
- Worked closely with the product team to gather user insights via user surveys and decide on product features.

CHECKLEARN, Lagos, Nigeria

JULY 2023 - NOVEMBER 2023

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

- During my four months internship at Check, I had the opportunity to improve my knowledge of JavaScript and fetching data. I built multiple projects that involved fetching data from different APIs.
- Code reviews and feedbacks were given by the team lead that helped to bring about better coding practices and improved and maintainable code
- Engaged in continuous learning to improve understanding of code structures and workflow.

SQOOLR, Lagos, Nigeria

NOVEMBER 2022 - OCTOBER 2023

— FRONT END ENGINEER

- Contributed to the development of SQOOLR's prototype, gaining valuable experience in the use of React and TypeScript.
- Collaborated with designers and backend engineers to build scalable and maintainable user interface for Sqoolr.
- Contributed to the continuous improvement and development by suggesting better practices and participating in code reviews with the rest of the team.

PROJECTS

Scissors App — Capstone project for AltSchool Africa

Scissors is a url-shortening app designed to make urls as short as possible, making links easier to use. It is built with Vue.js and Typescript for the frontend and Firebase was used for authentication and data storage

Scissors

Github Repository App — Fetches repositories from user's github

The website interacts with the github API to fetch and display repositories from the users GitHub profile. Website was built with React.js, Tailwind Css, Chakra ui and framer.

Repo

EDUCATION

AltSchool Africa

SEPTEMBER 2023 - AUGUST 2024

— Software Engineering (Front End)

University of Lagos, Lagos, NigeriaBachelors of Physiotherapy (BPT)

JANUARY 2020 - DATE

LANGUAGES

English, Yoruba